Kishan Narotam

Senior Associate Consultant +27 72 619 1929 knarotam@gmail.com knarotam.github.io Johannesburg, South Africa KEY SKILLS Time & Self Management Communication Leadership Complex Problem Solving Analytical Skills (Business and Data)

EDUCATION

Software Development

MBA in Business Analytics

Universidad Catolica San Antonio de Murcia | Spain to be completed in 2022

Postgraduate Extended Diploma in Business Management

Cambridge International Qualifications | UK to be completed in 2022

Bachelor of Science in Engineering (Electrical) Information

University of the Witwatersrand | South Africa 2019

IEB National Senior Certificate with Advanced Programme Mathematics

St John's College | South Africa 2012

INDUSTRIES

Logistics & Market Research Education & Training ICT (Information & Communication Technologies) Engineering Insurance

***** DEMOGRAPHICS

Gender · Male
Disability · None
Race · Indian
Languages · English

Banking

PROFESSIONAL PROFILE

Senior Associate Consultant currently working as a *Data Analyst* at *IQbusiness*, with an always learning mentality and seeks to apply himself to his maximum potential. Having worked on various projects where his role ranged from lead engineer to a business analyst and a data analyst, Kishan's approach to work is methodical and analytical. The execution of the task is planned accordingly, to complete all objectives in the most efficient and successful manner so that the maximum value can be added. Kishan is in the process of completing his MBA specialised in Business Analytics through UCAM University.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Senior Associate Consultant · IQbusiness | Johannesburg, South Africa # 11/02/2021 - Current

Responsibilities: Kishan is consulting to Nedbank as a Data Analyst within the Ghost Team in optimising the overall data management process. This includes sourcing data in order to create the baseline metric; creating a dashboard and report that can be presented to both business and technical stakeholders; ensuring POPIA compliance in all processes and implementations.

Associate Consultant

29/01/2020 - 11/02/2021

Responsibilities: Kishan has worked as a business analyst on an internal project as well as an external project. He has successfully performed the role of a Data Analyst for Genex Insights and worked as an analyst within Absa's model risk space that would lead to a tactical journey in 2021.

Teaching Assistant · University of the Witwatersrand | Johannesburg, South Africa

07/2019 - 10/2019

m 07/2018 - 10/2018

Responsibilities: Kishan was required to help run, execute and demonstrate laboratories and tutorials. In doing so he required extensive knowledge of C++, SFML, GitHub and Git collaboration. Throughout the course, Kishan assisted the students in a variety of ways relating to their work.

Intern · Liberty Life Head Office | Johannesburg, South Africa

07/2017

28/11/2016 - 18/01/2017

06/05/2016 - 17/06/2016

Responsibilities: Kishan worked in the IT department of the company assisting the HOD in various projects. The projects tasked to Kishan ranged from data collection, database management, network mapping, system analysis, C++ and VBA programming and Excel programming.

Responsibilities: Kishan was challenged with analysing C# code for an ongoing project and was tasked with converting the project into C++. Following this, Kishan had to design and implement a basic user interface for the analysed code.

Kishan Narotam

</> **TOOLKIT**

Software Development

Project Management

Scrum · Kanban · MS Project · Trello · Test Driven Development

Databases

MySQL · MS Access · Netezza

Continuous Integration

GII

Analysis

MS Excel · Power BI · Tableau

Technical Writing

MS Word \cdot MS PowerPoint \cdot MS Outlook \cdot MS Visio \cdot LaTeX

Graphical Editing

Adobe Premiere Pro



IBM (Coursera)

Data Science Professional Certificate (IBM Data Science) · 16/01/2021

Data Science Foundations Specialization · 08/12/2020

Applied Data Science Capstone · 16/01/2021

Machine Learning with Python · 14/01/2021

Data Analysis with Python · 24/12/2020

Databases and SQL for Data Science · 08/12/2020

Python for Data Science and AI · 01/12/2020

Data Science Methodology · 20/11/2020

Tools for Data Science · 17/11/2020

Data Science Orientation · 10/11/2020

Microsoft

MTA: Database Fundamentals: Certificate 2020 15/09/2020

ICAgile

ICAgile Certified Professional · 04/05/2020

Tableau

Tableau Author · 29/05/2020 Tableau Consumer · 26/05/2020

IQbusiness

UX Design Bootcamp · 21/08/2020

UiPath Academy

RPA Business Analyst Foundation · 12/08/2020 RPA Starter Training · 03/03/2020



ONLINE PROFILE

in /in/kishan-y-narotam/
// /KNarotam

PROJECT EXPERIENCE

Data Analyst · Ghost Squad

Nedbank Group | Johannesburg, South Africa

01/02/2021 - Current

Project Overview: The Ghost ecosystem is responsible for unsecured lending in Nedbank, namely credit card, personal loan, overdraft and home loans. The overall objective is to optimise the pipeline and its environment to ensure improved efficiency and monitoring while complying to regulations. This includes documenting all necessary process; understanding and analysing all procedures and subsequent data.

Responsibilities: Kishan has created a holistic document that entails detailed explanations and process diagrams of the Ghost pipelines' procedures, source to target mapping and solutions and analysis of various queries; being made available in a centralised location. Kishan has also analysed various optimisation implementations, documenting and creating a dashboard for ongoing monitoring and evaluation that can be utilised by both business and technical teams alike. Kishan was also tasked in analysing the processes within the pipeline and ensuring and documenting all POPIA related aspects ensuring compliance of the system.

Analyst · Model Risk Data Discovery and Design Absa Group Limited | Johannesburg, South Africa

28/07/2020 - 11/12/2020

Data Analyst · MultiChoice Africa Genex Insights | Johannesburg, South Africa

09/03/2020 - 31/07/2020

Business Analyst · IQbusiness Talent Management Solution IQbusiness | Johannesburg, South Africa

06/02/2020 - 25/02/2020

Business Analyst · IAM AfricaAccess | CSO Testing Proposal Absa Group Limited | Johannesburg, South Africa

30/01/2020 - 04/02/2020

Lead Engineer · Design of a Thermally Controlled System for Medications University of the Witwatersrand | Johannesburg, South Africa

17/09/2019 - 25/10/2019

 $\textbf{Co-Lead Engineer} \cdot \text{Image Compression Based on Non-Parametric Sampling in Noisy Environments}$

University of the Witwatersrand | Johannesburg, South Africa

01/07/2019 - 11/09/2019

For a more comprehensive view of all certificates; testimonials; projects and subsequent responsibilities can be found on CV tab of my website or at the link below.

https://knarotam.github.io/Pages/CV/CV.html